Finding Aid for the Sephardic Temple Tifereth Israel Records LSC.2340
UCLA Library Special Collections
Sephardic Temple Tifereth Israel records
1905 to 2017, bulk 1920-2005
1920-2005
UCLA Library Special Collections
Sephardic Temple Tifereth Israel (Los Angeles, Calif.)
LSC.2340
42 linear feet (53 boxes, 7 cartons, 6 shoe boxes, 14 flat boxes, 1 tube, 1 oversize flat box, 1 oversize folder)
Collection consists of records from the organized Sephardic Jewish community of Los Angeles and other materials related to Sephardic life in 20th century Los Angeles.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Access to digital materials is available on-site in the Special Collections reading room. Requests to access digital materials must be made at least 2 days in advance. Once request has been made, please confirm viewing arrangements with Special Collections reference desk staff.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIO AND AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audio and audiovisual materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email spec-coll@library.ucla.edu.
PORTIONS OF THIS COLLECTION HAVE BEEN DIGITIZED. Please consult digital facsimiles instead of originals.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Alex Rachmanony, STTI President, 2016.
About the Archive
This collection forms part of UCLA's Sephardic Archive Initiative.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9988323433606533
Custodial History
Materials in this collection were collected by Maurice Hattem and an archival team made up of members of STTI. The bulk of these materials were collected in the 1980s.
Biographical / Historical
After centuries of established life on the Iberian Peninsula, Jews were formally expelled by Spanish royal decree in 1492. With many refugees settling in North Africa and the Ottoman Empire, these Jews developed a distinct Sephardic (meaning Spanish, in Hebrew) culture and community that included the retention and development of a unique hybrid language, known as Judeo-Spanish or Ladino. At the outset of the 20th century, these Sephardic Jews sought better futures elsewhere, such as in sub-Saharan Africa, Western Europe, South America, and the United States. In search of economic opportunity and respite from political turmoil in the crumbling Ottoman Empire, many of these Sephardic Jews found their way to Los Angeles, a rapidly growing commercial and industrial metropolis. Throughout the century, the Sephardic community in Los Angeles would expand and come to include Jews from various backgrounds, notably North African, Israeli, and Persian Jews. By the end of the century, Los Angeles had solidified its status as a center of Sephardic life worldwide.
The Comunidad Sefardi de Los Angeles (Sephardic Community of Los Angeles) was officially formed in 1920 by a few dozen young immigrant men, though its roots go back to 1912 with the formation of Ahavat Shalom (Love of Peace). Catering to members from cities along Turkey's Mediterranean coast - like Istanbul, Bursa, and Izmir - these organizations were simultaneously religious, social, cultural, and economic in nature. Soon after in 1921, another Sephardic organization, Haim vaHessed (Life and Kindness), was formed and later changed its name to the Sephardic Brotherhood. The center of Sephardic life was to be found primarily in and around downtown until the 1930s, when it moved southwest towards South Los Angeles and the Exposition Park area. The Community's synagogue, Tifereth Israel, was inaugurated in 1932 and built on Santa Barbara Avenue, now Martin Luther King Jr. Boulevard. In 1959, a congregational merger created the Sephardic Community and Brotherhood of Los Angeles. Beginning in 1967, plans for a new temple in Westwood were underway that were ultimately realized during a final dedication ceremony in 1981. Over time, the organization and synagogue names would both be identified as the Sephardic Temple Tifereth Israel (STTI), as it is known at the time of processing (2019).
Parallel to and closely intertwined with STTI is another Sephardic congregation in Los Angeles that was formed in 1917 as Sociedad Pas i Progreso (Peace and Progress Society) and consisted mainly of Jews from the Island of Rhodes. In 1935, after inaugurating a synagogue in South Los Angeles at 55th St. and Hoover, they changed their name to the Sephardic Hebrew Center. After moving their temple to Ladera Heights in the late 1960s, SHC changed their name to Sephardic Beth Shalom in 1992, only to merge with Sephardic Temple Tifereth Israel (STTI) in 1993.
These organizations each had their own women's groups - known as Sisterhoods or Ladies' Auxiliaries - that catered to their members' social, philanthropic, and communal needs. Through the late 1950s and early 1960s, the Brotherhood, Community, Sephardic Hebrew Center, and their corresponding women's groups joined together in a short-lived Council of Sephardic Organizations, which mainly coordinated fundraising and social events.
Other Sephardic organizations represented in this collection are the Maccabeans - a semi-independent young adult group - and the Sephardic Benevolent Society, alongside the Los Angeles Sephardic Home for the Aged (LASHA) and other local, national, and international Sephardic and Jewish organizations, programs, and groups.
Scope and Content
The Sephardic Temple Tifereth Israel records consist of materials related to the Sephardic Temple Tifereth Israel (STTI) and its lay and religious leadership and congregants, as well as items of broader relevance to Sephardic and Jewish life in Los Angeles, California, the United States, and abroad. The collection includes organizational records, such as board meeting minutes, correspondence, event programs and tribute journals, publications, ephemera, photographs, scrapbooks, subject and research files, assorted awards and honors, 1/4 inch audiotapes of Sephardic, Balkan, and Turkish music collected by Emily Sene, and VHS and audiocassettes of STTI events. The bulk of the collection is in English and to a lesser extent Ladino.
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged in the following series and sub-series:
Series 1: Institutional records, 1920-2017
Subseries 1.1: Minutes, 1920-2005
Subseries 1.2: Building and financial records, 1929-2017
Subseries 1.3: Organizational records, committee records, and official correspondence, 1920-2009
Series 2: Publications, newsletters, and programs, 1932-2015
Subseries 2.1: Newsletters and publications, 1946-2015
Subseries 2.2: Programs, yearbooks, events, 1932-2015
Series 3: Subject files, 1905-2014
Subseries 3.1: Maurice I. "Bob" Hattem papers, 1922-2005
Subseries 3.2: Personal files, 1911-2014
Subseries 3.3: Place files, 1905-2003
Series 4: Photographs, scrapbooks, and clippings, circa 1910-2004
Subseries 4.1: Photographs, 1910-2001
Subseries 4.2: Scrapbooks and clippings, 1910-2004
Series 5: Audiovisual, 1951-2004
Subseries 5.1: Sene collection, 1953-1980
Subseries 5.2: Other audiovisual materials, 1951-2004
Series 6: Awards, artwork, and ephemera, 1911-2002
Subseries 6.1: Awards, plaques, certificates, drawings, 1911-2002
Subseries 6.2: Ephemera, 1913-1990
Digitized Facsimilies Available
PORTIONS OF THIS COLLECTION HAVE BEEN DIGITIZED. Please consult digital facsimiles instead of originals.
Separated Materials
Ladino books have been individually cataloged in the UCLA Library online catalog. Records for these items may be found by searching this keyword string: "Sephardic Temple Tifereth Israel records."
Related Materials
Western States Jewish History Archive (LSC 1739). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.
Sephardim -- California -- Los Angeles; Sephardic Temple Tifereth Israel (Los Angeles, Calif.) -- Archives
- Series 1: Institutional records, 1920-2017
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains minutes, tax and financial records, official correspondence, membership information, architectural/building records, and legal records of a few interrelated Sephardic organizations, mostly based in Los Angeles. These include the Comunidad Sefardi/Sephardic Community/Sephardic Temple Tifereth Israel, Haim vaHessed/Sephardic Brotherhood, the Sephardic Hebrew Center/Sephardic Beth Shalom, the Council of Sephardic Organizations, the Sephardic Benevolent Society, and the Sephardic Sisterhood (affiliated with the Community).
  - Subseries 1.1: Minutes, 1920-2005
    Sub-series 1.1 contains the minutes of general, special, committee, and board meetings of the various Sephardic groups mentioned above, with the bulk relating to the Comunidad/Community/STTI.
    - Comunidad minutes, 1920-1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Comunidad minutes, 1938-1946 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Comunidad minutes, 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Community minutes, 1949-1956 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Community minutes, 1956-1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Community minutes, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Community and brotherhood board meeting minutes, 1961-1965 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Community and brotherhood board meeting minutes, 1965-1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Community and brotherhood board meeting minutes, 1971-1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Community and brotherhood general meeting minutes, 1960-1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - STTI board meeting minutes, 1978-1987 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - STTI board and board of directors meeting minutes, 1987-1990 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - STTI board and board of directors meeting minutes, 1991-1999 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - STTI board and board of directors meeting minutes, 2000-2005 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Sephardic Hebrew Center minutes, 1942-1960 (Box 5)
    - Sephardic Hebrew Center minutes, 1968-1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Sephardic Sisterhood minutes, 1958-1960 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Sephardic Benevolent Society minutes, 1961-1971 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 1.2: Building and financial records, 1929-2017
    Sub-series 1.2 contains institutional, building, legal, and financial records relating to STTI, much of it from the papers of Richard J. Amado (born 1902 in Smyrna/Izmir, Ottoman Turkey and died 1984 in Los Angeles). Amado was a lawyer and local lay leader in the Sephardic and Jewish community, particularly in the Comunidad/Community and the Council of Sephardic Organizations, where he was president for several years. Sub-series 1.2 also contains some of Amado's correspondence and other documents relating to his other communal roles from the 1930s through the 1970s.
    - Sephardic Community Santa Barbara Ave Temple construction, 1929-1933 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Sephardic Community Santa Barbara Temple Planning and Groundbreaking, 1929-1932 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Sephardic Community tax exemption case, 1941-1943 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Sephardic Community and Brotherhood Temple site search, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Sephardic Community/STTI financial miscellany, 1956-1992 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - STTI Westwood temple zoning, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Temple construction and miscellaneous, 1967-1970 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Westwood temple construction and plans, 1969-1972 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - STTI Michael Alcana Youth Lounge, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - STTI Tour Guides and other miscellaneous, 1975-2000 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - STTI Library and Museum, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - STTI Finances and Stocks, 1972-1978 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Richard J. Amado papers: STTI finances and stocks, 1957-1976 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Richard J. Amado papers: STTI securities, 1972-1979 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Richard J. Amado papers: correspondence, miscellaneous, 1959-1973 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Richard J. Amado papers: correspondence, miscellaneous, 1960-1973 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Richard J. Amado papers: correspondence, miscellaneous, 1971-1975 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Richard J. Amado papers: incorporation, taxes, exemption, 1959-1980 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Richard J. Amado papers: tax exemption, 1963-1976 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Richard J. Amado papers: gifts and memorials, 1968-1980 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Richard J. Amado papers: Sephardic Home for Aged, 1956-1979 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Richard J. Amado papers: temple finances, Gorme-Lawrence documents, secret fund, 1973-1984 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Richard J. Amado papers: Israel bonds, creditor claim, 1960-1976 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Richard J. Amado Papers: Malinow and Silverman Mortuary, 1973-1980 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Richard J. Amado papers: STTI building and construction, 1969-1978 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Richard J. Amado papers: Old temple heritage site, sanctuary construction, re-dedication, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Tentative architectural plans for STTI - Leroy Miller AIA architecture, 1967 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - STTI museum and library architectural plans, 1976; Architectural plans are rolled, but in good condition. (Box 75)
    - Sephardic Sisterhood financial documents, 1961-1978 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Sephardic Sisterhood financial documents, 1975-1977 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 1.3: Organizational records, committee records, and official correspondence, 1920-2009
    Sub-series 1.3 contains material of relevance to the institutions of Sephardic life in Los Angeles, such as those related to constitutions and by-laws, membership, committees, events, fundraising, and correspondence with other local, national, and international organizations. These are mostly from STTI, but some are from the Sephardic Sisterhood, the Council of Sephardic Organizations, and the Sephardic Hebrew Center.
    - STTI Temple dedications, 1932, 1970, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - STTI membership dues and lists, 1921-1997 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - STTI membership lists and guide to Sephardic Los Angeles, 1990-1998 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - STTI membership lists, 2006, 2009 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - STTI constitutions and amendments, 1930-1995 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - STTI constitutions and amendments, 1920-1952 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - STTI Board of Directors, 1957-2003 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Committees: Talmud Torah and education, 1956-1999 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Committees: Adult education, 1979-1993 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Committees: Membership lists, 1951-1990 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Committees: Burial, 1937-2001 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Committees: Archives, 1983-2000 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Committees: Publications and El Shofar, 1979-1993 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Committees: Elections, Religious, Special, 1956-2002 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Maurice Amado Scholarship Award, 1973-1980 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - STTI correspondence, 1929-1965 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - STTI correspondence, 1970-2001 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Fountain pen from STTI cornerstone, 1931 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Documents from STTI Cornerstone, 1920-1931 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - United Sephardic Organizations/Council of Sephardic Organizations documents, 1938-1950 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Merger of Sephardic Community and Brotherhood and ephemera, 1952-1965 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Sisterhood history, 1924-1935, 1999; Oversize, pages contained in leather souvenir container. Fragile paper. (Box 71)
    - Sephardic Sisterhood: constitutions, correspondence, membership lists, 1931-1997 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Sisterhood documents, 1971-1996 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Suzanne Amado papers and other Sisterhood items, 1936-2015 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Haim vaHessed Society, 1933-1936 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Sephardic Hebrew Center: constitutions, correspondence, events, 1938-1982 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - STTI-Sephardic Hebrew Center merger, 1992-1993 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Affiliated organizations: Alliance Israelite Universelle, American Sephardi Federation, Bureau of Jewish Education, 1956-2000 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Affiliated organizations: City of Hope, Home of Peace, Israel Bonds, Jewish war veterans, the Ladinos, Los Angeles Sephardic Home for the Aged, 1934-2000 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Affiliated organizations: Los Amigos Sefaradis, Los Hermanos, Los Merecidos award, Material for Palestine, the Maccabeans, 1948-1997 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Affiliated organizations: Mt. Sinai hospital, Senior Citizens, Sephardic Education Center, United Jewish Welfare Fund, World Sephardi Federation, 1935-2002 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Series 2: Publications, newsletters, and programs, 1932-2017
  This series contains various publications and newsletters from Los Angeles-based Sephardic organizations, from the 1940s until 2017. Most are from the Sephardic Community and Brotherhood/STTI, and their El Shofar monthly bulletin features a near-complete collection through the 2000s from its first issue in 1980. Its long-time editor, Bob Hattem, also served as the STTI main archivist. Other publications include those from the Sephardic Hebrew Center and the Los Angeles Sephardic Home for the Aged (LASHA). This series also includes items related to cultural, religious, and social events and programs organized by or with various Sephardic organizations in Los Angeles.
  - Subseries 2.1: Newsletters and publications, 1946-2015
    Sub-series 2.1 contains printed newsletters and bulletins from Los Angeles Sephardic groups, primarily from the Sephardic Community/Sephardic Temple Tifereth Israel (variously published as Tifereth Israel Bulletin, La Vida Sefardi, Sephardic Messenger, STTI News, STTI Bulletin, and El Shofar). Other items include publications from the Sephardic Hebrew Center (variously published as Sephardic Hebrew Center Monthly, Sephardic Star, Sephardic News), the Council of Sephardic Organizations, the Sephardic Sisterhood, and the Los Angeles Sephardic Home for the Aged's LASHON.
    - Sephardic Hebrew Center Monthly, Sephardic Star, Sephardic News, 1963-1985 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Sephardic Council News, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Tifereth Israel Bulletin, La Vida Sefardi, 1946-1966 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Sephardic Messenger, 1960-1962 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Sephardic Messenger, 1963-1968 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Temple Tifereth Israel Bulletin, 1966-1971 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Sephardic Messenger, STTI News, STTI Bulletin, 1972-1979 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Sephardic Sisterhood News Bulletin, 1948, 1974-1976 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - El Shofar, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - El Shofar, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - El Shofar, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - El Shofar, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - El Shofar, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - El Shofar, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - El Shofar, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - El Shofar, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - El Shofar, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - El Shofar, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - El Shofar, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - El Shofar, 1991 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - El Shofar, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - El Shofar, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - El Shofar, 1994-1995 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - El Shofar, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - El Shofar, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - El Shofar, 1998 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - El Shofar, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - El Shofar, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - El Shofar, 2001 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - El Shofar, 2002-2005 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - El Shofar, 2006-2011 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - El Shofar, 2012-2017 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - LASHON, 1986-1992 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - LASHON, 1993-1994 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - LASHON, 1995-1999 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - LASHON, 2000-2002 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - LASHON, 2002-2004 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - LASHON, 2004-2011 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous publications, 1982-2015 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 2.2: Programs, yearbooks, and events, 1932-2015
    Sub-series 2.2 features programs, brochures, flyers, and other items related to community events and celebrations. Includes Sephardic Heritage Award journals from STTI, annual yearbooks from the Sephardic Hebrew Center, as well as items related to outside organizations like the Maccabeans, Los Angeles Sephardic Home for the Aged, and the Sephardic Hebrew Academy (now the Gindi Maimonides Academy). Sub-series 2.2 also contains some curricular and liturgical items from STTI.
    - Programs, 1932-1981 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - The Maccabeans - Miss Sephardic, 1954-1964 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Sephardic Community and Brotherhood event programs and journals, 1935-1964 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Sephardic Community and Brotherhood event programs and journals, 1966-1970 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - STTI dinner journals, 1975-1976 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - LASHA 30th anniversary journal, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Cantor Isaac Behar journal, 1997 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Sephardic Hebrew Academy scholarship dinner journal, 1992 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - STTI dinner journals, 1977-1978 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - STTI tribute journals and event programs, 1980-1983 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - STTI event programs and journals, 1983-1988 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Sephardic Heritage Award journal, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - STTI event programs and journals, 1989-1994 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - STTI events and journals, 1993-1997 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - STTI events, programs, and journals, 1998-2000 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - STTI events, programs, and journals, 2002-2004 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous events and ephemera, 1958-2015 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Events: Holocaust memorial, Sephardic Heritage Award, Voice of the Turtle, Sephardic Fiesta '79, Sephardic singles, 75th anniversary, 1977-2015 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - STTI memorial books, 1976-1980 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - STTI memorial books, 1981-1992 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - STTI memorial books, 1997-2015 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Sephardic Hebrew Center journals and yearbooks, 1967-1975 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Sephardic Hebrew Center journals and yearbooks, 1976-1978 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Sephardic Hebrew Center journals and yearbooks, 1980-1981 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Sephardic Hebrew Center journals and yearbooks, 1982, 1984 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Sephardic Hebrew Center journals and yearbooks, 1985-1987 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Sephardic Hebrew Center journals and yearbooks, 1988-1989 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Sephardic Hebrew Center/Sephardic Beth Shalom journals and yearbooks, 1990-1992 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - STTI yearbooks, 1994-1996 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Sephardic Community and Brotherhood, Council of Sephardic Organizations events and invitations, 1932-1979 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Events and invitations, 1980-1990 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Events and invitations, 1991-2000 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Events and invitations, weekly calendars, 1991-2004 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Shabbat Shalom fliers, 1978-1987 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Shabbat Shalom fliers, 1988-1993 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Shabbat Shalom fliers, 1994-2002 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Shabbat Shalom fliers, 2003-2005, 2014 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Talmud Torah materials, 1961-2001 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Talmud Torah materials, 1939-1991 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Religious materials: High Holidays and Passover, 1963-1990 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Religious materials: Shabbat and other holidays, 1981-1998 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Prayers for Israel and miscellaneous religious items and songs, 1930-1999 (Box 34, Folder 3)
- Series 3: Subject files, 1905-2014